<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dsl-extension kind="buildStep" type="FxCop" generateDslJar="true">
  <class name="FxCopStep">
    <description>
      An [FxCop build step](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/teamcity/?FxCop) is intended for inspecting .NET assemblies
      and reporting possible design, localization, performance, and security improvements.
    </description>
  </class>
  <function name="fxCop">
    <description>
      Add an [FxCop build step](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/teamcity/?FxCop).
      @see FxCopStep
    </description>
  </function>
  <params>

    <param name="fxcop.detection_mode" dslName="fxCopInstallation" type="compound">
      <description>
        When a build agent is started, it detects automatically whether FxCop is installed.
        If FxCop is detected, TeamCity defines the %system.FxCopRoot% agent system property.
        You can also use a custom installation of FxCop or the use FxCop checked in your version control.
      </description>

      <option name="auto" value="auto">
        <description>
          Select to use the FxCop installation on an agent.
        </description>
        <param name="fxcop.version" dslName="version" type="FxCopVersion">
          <description>
            The FxCop version required by the build; the agent requirement will be created.
            To use any version auto-detected on the agent side, set to 'ANY_DETECTED'.
          </description>
        </param>
      </option>

      <option name="manual" value="manual">
        <description>
          Select to use a custom installation of FxCop (not the autodetected one),
          or if you do not have FxCop installed on the build agent
          (for example, you can place the FxCop tool in your source control, and check it out with the build sources).
        </description>
        <param name="fxcop.root" dslName="installationRoot" mandatory="true">
          <description>
            The path to the FxCop installation root on the agent machine or
            the path to an FxCop executable relative to the Build Checkout Directory.
          </description>
        </param>
      </option>

    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.what" dslName="inspectionSource" type="compound">

      <option name="assemblies" value="files">
        <param name="fxcop.files" dslName="files" mandatory="true">
          <description>
            Enter the paths to the assemblies to be inspected (use Ant-like wildcards to select files by a mask).
            FxCop will use default settings to inspect them.
            The paths should be relative to the Build Checkout Directory and separated by spaces.

            Note that there is a limitation to the maximum number of assemblies
            that can be specified here due to command-line string limitation.
          </description>
        </param>
        <param name="fxcop.files_exclude" dslName="exclude">
          <description>
            Exclude wildcards to refine the included assemblies list.

            Assembly file names relative to the checkout root separated by spaces.
            Ant-like wildcards are supported. Example: bin*.dll
          </description>
        </param>
      </option>

      <option name="project" value="project">
        <param name="fxcop.project" dslName="projectFile" mandatory="true">
          <description>
            The FxCop project file name relative to the checkout root.
          </description>
        </param>
      </option>

    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.search_in_gac" dslName="searchInGAC" type="boolean" trueValue="true" falseValue="">
      <description>
        Search the assemblies referenced by targets in Global Assembly Cache.
      </description>
    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.search_in_dirs" dslName="searchInDirs">
      <description>
        Search the assemblies referenced by targets in the specified directories separated by spaces.
        Sets /d: options for FxCopCmd
      </description>
    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.ignore_generated_code" dslName="ignoreGeneratedCode" type="boolean" trueValue="true" falseValue="">
      <description>
        Sets /ignoregeneratedcode for FxCopCmd (note: it's supported since FxCop 1.36).
        Speeds up inspection.
      </description>
    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.report_xslt" dslName="reportXSLTFile">
      <description>
        The path to the XSLT transformation file relative to the Build Checkout Directory or absolute on the agent machine.
        You can use the path to the detected FxCop on the target machine (i.e. %system.FxCopRoot%/Xml/FxCopReport.xsl).
        When the Report XSLT file option is set, the build runner will apply an XSLT transform to FxCop XML output and
        display the resulting HTML in a new FxCop tab on the build results page.
      </description>
    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.addon_options" dslName="additionalOptions">
      <description>
        Additional options for calling FxCopCmd executable.
        All entered options will be added to the beginning of the command line parameters.
      </description>
    </param>

    <param name="fxcop.fail_on_analysis_error" dslName="failOnAnalysisError" type="boolean" trueValue="true" falseValue="">
      <description>
        Fails build on analysis errors from FxCop such as:
        ANALYSIS_ERROR, ASSEMBLY_LOAD_ERROR, ASSEMBLY_REFERENCES_ERROR,
        PROJECT_LOAD_ERROR, RULE_LIBRARY_LOAD_ERROR, UNKNOWN_ERROR, OUTPUT_ERROR
      </description>
    </param>

  </params>
  <types>
    <enum name="FxCopVersion">
      <option name="ANY_DETECTED" value="not_specified"/>
      <option name="v1_35" value="1.35"/>
      <option name="v9_0" value="9.0"/>
      <option name="v10_0" value="10.0"/>
      <option name="v12_0" value="12.0"/>
      <option name="v14_0" value="14.0"/>
      <option name="v15_0" value="15.0"/>
      <option name="v16_0" value="16.0"/>
    </enum>
  </types>
</dsl-extension>